Doctor Who (1963) 04x09  The Evil of the Daleks (Episode 1)
《神秘博士》老版第四季第九集 《Daleks 的邪恶》 (第一部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
Sincro: wyxchari
(Gatwick airport. The TARDIS is beging taken away on the back of a lorry.)
(伦敦盖特威克机场。TARDIS被放到一辆拖车上, 拖走了。)
DOCTOR: Jamie!
JAMIE: The TARDIS! Doctor!
我们的TARDIS! 博士!
(追了半天没有追上, 博士和 Jamie 进了刚才拖车所在的楼, 这里是一个机库)
DOCTOR: Excuse me!
打扰一下！
HALL: Eh?
嗯？
(Hall turn up the volume on his hearing aid.)
(Hall 调大了他的助听器的音量。)
JAMIE: I wonder if you could help us?
请问你可否帮我们一下？
HALL: My mate likes the wireless turned on at full blast.
我的同事喜欢把无线电开到最大声
HALL: I have to keep this turned down.
我就不得不把这个拿下来
DOCTOR: Oh, I see.
哦, 我明白了
JAMIE: Who's taken the TARDIS?
谁拖走了我的 TARDIS ?
DOCTOR: He means the police telephone box.
他说的是那个警用电话亭
HALL: He said 'TARDIS' or something.
但他说了 TARDIS 什么的
DOCTOR: Yes. Well, TARDIS... That's, uh...
hat's another name for it.
对, 这个, TARDIS 是．．那是另外一个名字
HALL: Oh, foreign is he?
哦, 他是外国人吧
JAMIE: Me, foreign? You're the one that's foreign! I'm Scottish!
我, 外国人？你才是外国人！我是苏格兰人
DOCTOR: Uh, that's right. TARDIS is a... is a Gaelic word. Jamie, hush!
啊, 那就对了．TARDIS 是盖尔语的说法．Jamie, 安静
DOCTOR: It's getting further away all the time!
它离我们越来越远了
JAMIE: Yes, I know.
是的, 我知道
DOCTOR: Well anyway, it's... it's our property
and we've come to collect it.
这样的, 这是．．．这是我们的财产, 我们是来认领的
HALL: Oh, you mean the...uh, the police box?
哦, 你是说这个．．．这个警用电话亭？
DOCTOR: Yes!
是的
HALL: Yeah. Well, uh... Well, that's gone.
哦, 但是．．．它不见了
DOCTOR: Oh, we...
哦, 我们．．．
JAMIE: ...know it's gone. That's the whole point.
Its ours and somebody's stolen it!
知道它不见了．这是问题的关键．它是我们的, 有人偷走了它
HALL: Ah, well, I don't know about that.
I got a note here somewhere.
啊, 我不知道怎么回事．我的笔记本呢？
HALL: Yeah, here we are. There.
"Police Tel. Box. Collection: 3 o'clock".
耶, 在这里．＂警用电话亭 登记时间：下午三点＂
DOCTOR: Let me see this please.
让我看一下
HALL: Been signed for.
签个名吧
DOCTOR: Oh, yes. So I see. Er... "J Smith".
Doesn't really help us, does it?
哦, 好的, 我明白了．嗯．．．"J Smith"．这好像帮不上我们什么啊, 对不
HALL: Yeah. Well, I just do what I'm told.
Better see the airport commandant or someone.
这个．．．我只能做这么多, 你们最好去找一下机场负责人什么的
DOCTOR: Oh, no. I... I don't think we'd better do that.
Um, Jamie, I think we'd better talk to the police.
哦, 不, 我．．我觉得我们最好不要去．唔, Jamie, 我觉得我们最好还是去找警察
HALL: Of course I, um... I do know the name of the firm what picked it up.
当然, 不过我还真知道是谁把它拖走了
DOCTOR: You do?!
你知道？
HALL: Yeah, firm name of, uh... Leatherman.
是的, 商号名字是．．．Leatherman
DOCTOR: Thank you very much. You'll be hearing from us.
非常谢谢你, 你会听到我们的消息的
JAMIE: Leatherman. Now that's a clue. Just a minute.
Now, what street do they...? Doctor, wait!
Leatherman．现在有一条线索了, 等一下, 他们在那条街．．？博士, 等一下
(博士出了机库, Jamie赶紧跟上)
HALL: Did you get all that?
你刚才听到了吗？
(原来 Hall 的助听器是假的, 其实是一个对话耳麦)
KENNEDY: Every word. We'd better get going.
Get your money back at the warehouse.
都听清了, 我们得马上过去．去仓库拿你的钱吧
(Kennedy 通过 Hall 的耳麦听到了他跟博士他们的对话)
JAMIE: We should have followed that clue he gave us.
我们应该沿着刚才他给我们那条线索走
DOCTOR: Perhaps. I think we'd better keep an eye on him.
也许吧, 我觉得我们最好盯着他
JAMIE: Why?
为什么
DOCTOR: Well, didn't you notice his overalls?
They were much too small for him,
你没有注意到他的工作服吗？对他来说有点太小了
DOCTOR: and the top sheet of his clipboard was different to all the others
而且他那个纸夹板最上面那页跟其它页都不一样
DOCTOR: And when we mentioned the police, he became friendly!
当我们说要去找警察的时候, 他就突然变得友好了
JAMIE: Aye. Hey, may...
是吧．嘿, 也许．．
(They hide as they see Hall approaching.)
(他俩看见 Hall 走了过来, 赶紧躲了起来)
(Once he has gone by, they follow him.)
(Hall 走了过去, 博士和 Jamie 跟在后面)
KENNEDY: Kennedy to base. Kennedy to base. Do you read me?
Kennedy 呼叫基地, Kennedy 呼叫基地, 你能听到吗
(刚才在偷听的 Kennedy 拿起对讲, 开始呼叫)
KENNEDY: Kennedy to base. Do you read?
Kennedy 呼叫基地, 你能听到吗
WATERFIELD: Yes.
听到
KENNEDY: The Doctor and his friend are following Bob Hall.
博士和他的同伴在跟踪 Bob Hall
WATERFIELD: I knew they would suspect him.
我就知道他们会怀疑他
KENNEDY: I'll go on to the warehouse.
我现在去仓库
WATERFIELD: Very good, Mr Kennedy.
很好, Kennedy 先生
(Hall goet into his car and drives off.)
(Hall 进了他的小汽车, 开走了。)
DOCTOR: That's him. There he goes.
就是他, 他去那儿了
JAMIE: Oh, no!
哦, 不
(The Doctor and Jamie hail a taxi and get in.)
(博士和 Jamie 招手拦住一辆出租车, 坐了进去)
DOCTOR: For hire!
租车
DRIVER: Eh?
嗯
DOCTOR: Follow that car!
跟住那辆车
WATERFIELD: Yes?
谁啊？
PERRY: Perry, sir.
我是 Perry
WATERFIELD: Oh, uh... One moment Mr. Perry.
哦, 稍等一下, Perry先生
PERRY: It's here.
我找到了
WATERFIELD: Good.
很好
PERRY: Like me to open the shutters, sir? Lovely day outside.
需要我打开百页窗吗, 先生？外面阳光不错
WATERFIELD: I have a choice between the sun or noise, Mr Perry.
我在阳光和噪音之间做了一个选择, Perry先生。
WATERFIELD: I regret shutting out one,
but at least I keep out the other.
虽然享受不到阳光有点可惜, 但至少噪音还是被挡住了
PERRY: Yes. I say! That's very good. Just come in, eh?
是的, 我得说！这件很不错, 进来吧
PERRY: Mint condition. Eighteen, uh, seventy. Is it?
条件也还不错, 是18世纪70年代的, 是吧？
WATERFIELD: Approximately.
差不多
PERRY: Don't know who your contacts are, sir, but this is marvellous!
不知道您的客户是谁, 先生, 不过这件非常棒！
WATERFIELD: Well, Victorian timepieces are my speciality, Mr. Perry.
是, 维多利亚时期的时钟算是我的专长, Perry先生
PERRY: Wish you'd tell me who makes them for you, sir.
真期望您能告诉我是谁给您做的, 先生
WATERFIELD: But then you would be as wise as I,
and that wouldn't do at all, would it?
那样的话你就跟我一样聪明了, 这样可行不通, 是吧？
PERRY: Whoever makes them, Mr. Waterfield, they'd fool an expert.
不管是谁吧, Waterfield 先生, 他们绝对可以骗过专家。
PERRY: If I didn't know it was impossible,
I would say it was absolutely genuine.
假设我并不知道这是不可能的, 我得说这件绝对是真品
WATERFIELD: And, uh, there was no trouble with the box?
另外, 盒子不会有什么问题吧
PERRY: Apparently not. A bit out of our line, isn't it, sir?
A battered old police box?
看起来不会。不过不在我们主线上啊, 不是吗, 先生？一座破旧的警用电话亭？
WATERFIELD: The whims and caprices of our patrons is our line, Mr Perry.
我们的主线就是让客户感到新奇、多变, Perry先生
PERRY: Hmm. Odd though.
唔, 还是有点怪
WATERFIELD: Mr Perry, I pay you the sum of 50 guineas per week, do I not?
Perry先生, 每星期我付给你50金币, 对不？
PERRY: Pounds, actually sir. 50 pounds.
英镑, 先生, 50英镑
WATERFIELD: Yes, uh... I hope I may be forgiven if I believe
that entitles me to demanding less curiosity of you.
是的, 哦。。。如果我觉得这可以允许我要求你少一点好奇心, 期望你不会觉得我太过分
PERRY: Sorry, sir.
抱歉, 先生
WATERFIELD: It is, I think you will agree, a princely salary.
我想你也同意, 这笔薪水是相当可观的
PERRY: No complaints on that score.
Long as I'm not asked to do anything dicey.
我对此完全满意。只要不让我去做一些太冒险的事情
WATERFIELD: "Dicey?"
“冒险？“
PERRY: Crooked. Illegal.
邪恶的, 非法的
WATERFIELD: Your candor is refreshing, Mr. Perry,
even if your judgement of character is somewhat questionable.
你还挺直率的, Perry 先生。不过你的他人的判断有点问题
PERRY: I didn't mean that...
我并不是这个意思。。。
WATERFIELD: I know perfectly well what you meant.
You may rest assured, I shall not ask you to do anything "dicey. "
我完全知道你什么意思。你放心吧, 我不会要求你做什么冒险的事情
PERRY: No, sir.
不会的, 先生
WATERFIELD: I think you are wanted in the shop, Mr. Perry.
我想你店里需要你, Perry先生
PERRY: And the, um... the telephone box, uh... What do we do with it?
不过那个。。。那个电话亭。。。我们拿它怎么办？
WATERFIELD: Do? We do nothing.
怎么办？什么也不办
PERRY: Oh, right.
哦, 好的
WATERFIELD: Nothing, except wait.
什么也不做, 就是等着
(The Doctor and Jamie are in a lane, walking towards a warehouse.)
(博士和 Jamie 在一个巷子里, 朝着一个仓库走去)
DOCTOR: This is his car. He must be around here somewhere.
这是他的车。他肯定就在这附近
WATERFIELD: You sure you weren't followed?
你肯定你没有被跟踪吗？
(Hall is counting a pile of five pound notes.)
(Hall 正在数钞票, 一叠都是5英镑面值的)
HALL: No! Course I wasn't. Hey, you haven't told me
what this little caper's about yet, uh, Kennedy.
没有, 当然没有。嘿, 你还没有告诉我这一切到底是怎么回事, Kennedy
KENNEDY: Counted the money yet then, have ya?
钱已经数过了, 对吗？
HALL: No, not yet.
没, 还没呢
KENNEDY: Or do you think I made a mistake giving ya two-fifty
instead of seventy-five? We thought you might like a little extra.
或许你认为我搞错了, 你说要75, 我却给了你250？我们是想你可以多拿一点
HALL: What for?
为什么？
KENNEDY: You know those two at the hangar?
你记得在机库的那两个家伙吧？
HALL: Yeah?
是啊？
KENNEDY: They're outside.
他们在外面
KENNEDY: You weren't followed!
你还说没被跟踪！
KENNEDY: We'll be ready for them, won't we? That's what the extra's for.
但我们得做点准备, 对吧。多给你的钱就为了这
KENNEDY: Now listen...
现在听着
(Kennedy picks up two sacks.)
(Kennedy 拿起两个口袋)
KENNEDY: You on one side of the door, me on the other. Right?
Straight over their heads. They won't even know what hit them.
你到门的这边, 我在那边, 行吧？直接对准他们的脑袋, 他们连是谁都不会知道
HALL: Ah, not me, mate.
啊？我不行, 伙计
KENNEDY: It's a bit late to argue, isn't it? They're outside.
现在才说有点太晚了吧, 是不？他们已经在外面了
HALL: Now listen, I'm not getting mixed up in a kidnapping, and that's flat!
听着, 我是不会卷入一场绑架的, 没得商量
KENNEDY: Oh, dear...
哦, 亲爱的
(Hall 不肯参与, Kennedy 拿起木棍打晕了 Hall, 跑了)
JAMIE: Doctor?
博士？
DOCTOR: Well, have you tried the door?
这里, 你试过这扇门吗？
(博士和 Jamie 看到了躺在地上的 Hall)
DOCTOR: Man in the overalls! It's all right. He's alive.
那个穿工作服的家伙！好了, 他还活着
HALL: Oh, dear... Where's Ken...
哦, 天啊, 哪儿去了Ken...
DOCTOR: Ken? Ken who?
Ken? Ken 什么？
JAMIE: Make him tell us where the TARDIS is!
让他告诉我们 TARDIS 哪儿去了!
DOCTOR: No good, he's out cold.
不太妙, 他晕过去了。
JAMIE: See if we can find some water somewhere.
看看我们能不能哪里找到一点水
DOCTOR: Hello, this is something. This really is something.
嘿, 这里有情况, 这里真有点情况
(The Doctor picks up the 5-pound notes.)
(博士捡起那些5英镑的钞票)
DOCTOR: But, why pay him to help steal the TARDIS
and then knock him on the head?
奇怪, 为什么付钱让他帮忙偷走 TARDIS, 又来砸他的头？
JAMIE: Well, why steal the TARDIS anyway?
到底为什么要偷 TARDIS 呢？
DOCTOR: That's what's been bothering me, Jamie, too.
这事儿我也想不清楚, Jamie
JAMIE: There's no water here. Hey, that looks a lot of money, Doctor.
这里没有水, 嘿, 这里看来有一大笔钱, 博士
DOCTOR: It's between two and three hundred pounds.
大概200多镑, 300不到。
DOCTOR: Yes, it is a lot, at least for what he had to do
这的确不少, 对于要他干的事情来说不少
DOCTOR: - put on a pair of overalls and just hang around.
—— 也就是穿上工作服晃悠两下
JAMIE: Come to think of it, why hang around? He was obviously planted.
Why not just go off in the lorry?
你想想, 为什么要晃悠？他显然是被安插下来的。为什么不跟着货车一起跑掉呢？
(The Doctor sees the cigarettes by the window.)
(博士看到了窗边的烟卷)
JAMIE: You found something else?
你找到了什么吗？
DOCTOR: I don't know.
我不知道
(Unnoticed, Hall opens and closes his eyes.)
(未被注意到的是, Hall 睁开了眼睛, 看了一眼又闭上了)
(The Doctor takes a small tin from Hall's pocket.)
(博士从 Hall 的口袋里面翻出一个小铁盒)
JAMIE: What's that?
那是什么？
DOCTOR: It's all right. It's only a train.
没事, 那是火车的声音
JAMIE: A what?
什么？
DOCTOR: Well, it's a train. There are carriages and
they go on wheels, on rails, and they're drawn by a stea...
嗯, 是火车。上面有车厢, 下面有轮子, 跑在铁轨上, 它们是靠蒸汽牵引着。。。
(Hall runs out, jamming the doors shut with a metal bar
through the handles.)
(Hall 突然跑了出去, 拿一个金属条别在门栓上, 卡住了门)
DOCTOR: Hey, come back!
嘿, 回来！
Well, give us a hand!
来, 搭把手
(The Doctor pulls the doors open.)
(博士拉开了门)
- DOCTOR: Aw, not a sign of him.
- JAMIE: The only chance we had.
- 啊, 不见踪影了  - 我们唯一的机会
DOCTOR: There is this...
还有这个。。。
(The Doctor shows Jammie a matchbox.)
(博士给 Jamie 看一个火柴盒子)
DOCTOR: "The Tricolour". It's a coffee bar apparently. And that's not all.
”三原色“。这看起来是一个咖啡馆。这还不是全部
JAMIE: Well, what else?
还有什么？
DOCTOR: Well, normally people pull out their matches from right to left.
These have been torn out from left to right.
看这个, 一般来说人们都是从右往左抽火柴。但这些是从左到右的
JAMIE: What does that mean?
这说明什么？
DOCTOR: It means we've got to find a coffee bar called "The Tricolour"
这说明我们要去一个叫做”三原色“的咖啡馆,
DOCTOR: and look for a man called Ken or Kenneth
- someone who's left-handed.
找寻一个叫做 Ken 或者 Kenneth 的人, 这人还是个左撇子
JAMIE: Now we've got something to go on!
现在我们找到地方继续
DOCTOR: But it's so little, Jamie. It's too little. He might only
have been there once. There's no guarantee he'll ever go there again.
机会还比较小, Jamie, 或者说非常小。他可能只去过那个地方一次, 不敢说他还会再去那里
JAMIE: Now, don't give up Doctor. Remember Bruce.
别放弃, 博士。记得 Bruce 吗？
DOCTOR: Bruce?
哪个 Bruce？
JAMIE: Robert Bruce.
(注：苏格兰独立运动领袖, 独立后的苏格兰国王罗伯特一世)
(The Docotor and Jamie leave the warehouse.)
(博士和 Jamie 离开了这个仓库)
KENNEDY: Look, I told...
看, 我跟你说过...
WATERFIELD: They were not aware that you were watching?
他们没有发现你在监视吗？
KENNEDY: No, they were too busy trying to work it all out.
没有, 他们一直忙着搞明白问题
WATERFIELD: Good.
很好
KENNEDY: That Bob Hall was a bit of a problem. I didn't think he'd turn nasty.
那个 Bob Hall 有点麻烦。我没想到他会变得棘手
WATERFIELD: You didn't hurt him?
你没有伤害他吧？
KENNEDY: Him? You're joking.
他？你开玩笑吧
WATERFIELD: I can assure you that I am not.
我可以保证我没有
KENNEDY: He's a lot bigger than me, you know.
No, I just baggered him one and that was it.
他比我块头大, 你知道的。没有, 我只是打了他一下, 仅此而已
WATERFIELD: That was what? Kennedy, I must know precisely
what has happened. How badly injured was Hall?
仅此而已？ Kennedy, 我必须知道到底发生了什么。Hall 伤得严重不？
KENNEDY: Well, a bit dazed, that's all. He just mumbled something
and made a run for it when they weren't looking.
就是有点晕了, 仅此而已。他嘟哝了几句什么, 然后趁他们没看见就跑了
WATERFIELD: And where is he now?
那他现在在哪儿？
KENNEDY: Well, I went round to his place later. There he was coming
out the front door, zip bag and everything. He got in a cab and went to Euston.
嗯, 我后来去了他的地方。他正从前门出来, 打包好了一切, 坐进一辆车, 去了 Euston
WATERFIELD: Were you able to find another hansom and follow him?
你就不能找个什么人跟着他吗？
KENNEDY: Eh?
嗯？
WATERFIELD: Did you follow him?
你跟踪他了？
KENNEDY: Yeah, yeah. Don't worry about him. He's gone up north.
好了, 好了, 别担心他了, 他去北方了
WATERFIELD: That disposes of that. Now, this is extremely important:
you did leave the matches?
那就估计没问题了。现在, 这个问题非常重要：你的确留下火柴了吗？
KENNEDY: Don't worry about it. The Doctor found the cigarettes and the matches.
别担心这个, 博士已经发现了烟卷和火柴
WATERFIELD: And you are certain they were the ones bearing the name of the coffee shop?
你确定就是带有咖啡店名称的那盒？
KENNEDY: Coffee bar.
咖啡馆
WATERFIELD: Yes.
对
KENNEDY: Yes. I told you, it worked like a charm. I never thought it would,
but you were quite right. He got onto the name on the matches straight away.
就是, 我跟你说, 进展非常顺利, 我都没想到。不过你是对的, 他直接就注意到了火柴上面的名字
WATERFIELD: Well, just one last thing, to make quite sure:
好, 最后一件事, 我得确认一下
(Waterfield opens a box, Kennedy is watching.
(Waterfield 打开一个盒子, Kennedy 凑前去看)
WATERFIELD: now you are certain that these are the people that you saw?
你看看, 你确认他们就是这两个人？
KENNEDY: That's them, yeah. Yeah, definite.
就是他们, 对的, 对的, 绝对
WATERFIELD: Right. Well, I shall want you to keep out of sight.
You'd better stay in the house, and on no account are you to
talk to Mr. Perry about any of this.
好。现在, 你先躲起来, 最好不要出门。也绝对不要跟 Perry 谈起这件事
KENNEDY: OK.
好吧
WATERFIELD: "OK."? What does that mean?
好吧？这什么意思？
KENNEDY: What? Yes!
什么? 好的！
WATERFIELD: Oh, I know that my attitude may appear strange to you on occasions, Kennedy.
哦, 我知道有时候我的态度会显得比较奇怪, Kennedy
KENNEDY: You want to play the part of the Victorian grandfather, that's all right by me.
你想要扮演维多利亚老爷爷, 这跟完全没关系。
KENNEDY: Must be a pretty good gimmick. You pay me well enough.
你这肯定是一个相当不错的局。不过你给我的报酬相当不错
WATERFIELD: It, uh... helps to sell to our customers.
这。。。对我们的生意有帮助
KENNEDY: Yeah, sure, sure. You've, uh... never told me
what it is exactly you've got against this Doctor and his friend.
对, 当然, 当然。你从来。。没有告诉过我, 你对博士和他的朋友到底有什么过节
KENNEDY: Some kind of vendetta or something?
是复仇什么的吗？
WATERFIELD: Explanations are not part of our arrangement.
我并没有必要向你解释
KENNEDY: Oh, just wondering.
哦, 只是好奇
WATERFIELD: Imagination is a virtue, but it can become a vice.
想象力是个优点, 但也可能变成缺点
KENNEDY: Mind me own business, yeah. I get the message.
管好我自己的事, 好, 我知道了
WATERFIELD: Ask Mr. Perry to come and see me, will you, please?
让 Perry 先生过来见我, 帮忙叫一下？
(Kennedy leaves the room.)
(Kennedy 离开了这个房间)
(Waterfield takes a key from the box and walks to the bookcase.)
(Waterfield 从箱子里拿起一把钥匙, 往书架走过去)
(Kennedy listening at the door.)
(Kennedy 在门口偷听)
(Waterfield inserts the key in a hole hidden behind a book.)
(Waterfield 把钥匙插进一个锁眼, 这个锁眼隐藏在一本书后面)
(He picks up a vase from the floor.)
(他从地方上拿起一个花瓶)
KENNEDY: He wants to see you.
他想要见你
PERRY: Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢你
WATERFIELD: Who is it?
谁？
PERRY: It's Perry, sir.
是 Perry, 先生
WATERFIELD: One moment.
等一下
PERRY: You wanted to see me, sir?
你想要见我, 先生？
WATERFIELD: Yes, I have an extremely important and delicate task
for you to perform.
是的, 我有一个非常重要、非常棘手的任务, 需要你去办
PERRY: Oh, yes?
哦, 是什么？
PERRY: I say, you got a new delivery.
咦, 你又有新货啦
WATERFIELD: Y... yes.
是。。是的
PERRY: I didn't see it arrive.
但我没有看到它送过来
WATERFIELD: It was delivered last night. I've only just
brought it in myself. It is, uh... for a new customer.
它是昨晚投递的, 我自己把它拿进来的。那是。。。那是给一个新客户的
PERRY: Oh, yes?
哦, 是吗？
WATERFIELD: A Dr. Galloway. He's extremely wealthy and an ardent collector...
某位 Galloway 博士, 他相当富有, 非常喜欢收藏
PERRY: Of, uh... Victoriana, sir?
当然。。。维多利亚迷, 是吗？
WATERFIELD: No less. I do not know the Doctor personally,
but we have arranged to meet in the coffee shop, uh... bar, nearby.
的确。我个人也不认识这位博士, 但我们约好了在附近的咖啡店, 哦, 咖啡馆, 见面
PERRY: Oh, the Tricolour, sir?
哦, 三原色, 是吗？
WATERFIELD: Yes. Unfortunately, I am unable to keep the appointment,
so I want you to go instead, Mr. Perry.
是的, 但不幸的是, 我没法赴约了。所以我想你替我去, Perry 先生。
WATERFIELD: Here is a photograph of Dr. Galloway.
这里有 Galloway 博士的照片
WATERFIELD: This is his assistant and secretary, Mr. James McCrimmon.
这是他的助手和秘书, James McCrimmon 先生.
WATERFIELD: Now I want you to ask the Doctor to come
to the shop tonight, say at, uh... ten o' clock.
我想让你请博士晚上到店里来, 大概。。10点
PERRY: Ten o'clock, sir?!
十点, 先生？
WATERFIELD: Yes. Oh, don't worry, Mr. Perry.
I shall be attending to him myself. You needn't wait.
是的。哦, 别担心, Perry 先生。我自己招待他, 你不用在这里等着
PERRY: Oh, right sir.
哦, 好的, 先生
WATERFIELD: The Doctor is notoriously unpunctual.
I fear you may have a long and tedious wait.
这位博士是出了名的不准时。恐怕你得多等一会儿了
PERRY: I shall find him sir. Do you want me to go now?
我会找到他的, 先生。你想让我现在就去吗？
WATERFIELD: If you please, Mr. Perry.
如果你愿意的话, Perry 先生
PERRY: Right.
好的
(Once Perry has gone, Kennedy continues to listen at the door.)
(Perry 一离开, Kennedy 回到门边继续偷听)
(Waterfield locks the study door, then walks to the bookcase.)
(Waterfield 锁上了书房门, 走到书架旁边)
(He sits in the chair.)
(他坐到椅子上)
PERRY: And what are you doing?
你在这里干什么？
KENNEDY: I... I can't make Mr. Waterfield hear me. I knocked.
我。。。刚才 Waterfield 先生听不见我说话。 我敲门了
PERRY: He's busy.
他正忙
KENNEDY: O.K. I'll try later.
好吧, 那我稍后再来
JAMIE: Don't look so depressed, Doctor.
别这么丧气, 博士
DOCTOR: If only we knew what he looked like, Jamie.
我们要是知道他长什么样子就好了, Jamie
JAMIE: We'll ask one of the lasses in a moment, when things get quieter.
我们一会儿问问某个女人, 要是还没什么头绪
DOCTOR: We've got to untangle this, you know.
我们得解开这个谜题，是吧
JAMIE: It's all quite obvious to me. They're just robbers.
Thieves, you understand.
对我而言，这非常明显, 他们就是抢劫犯, 小偷, 你明白吗？
DOCTOR: No, no, there's more to it than that.
Why leave that man in the hangar to give us a clue?
不, 不, 这事没那么简单。为什么要在机库留一个人给我们留下线索呢？
JAMIE: Which we haven't followed up, you know. "Leatherman?"
我们并没有跟着那条线索啊, 记得吗, ”Leatherman"
DOCTOR: There is no delivery firm of that name.
Not in the London area, anyway. I checked in the phone book.
没有哪个送货公司叫那个名字, 至少伦敦地区没有。我查过电话本了
JAMIE: But surely there's more places than London.
但显然不止伦敦这一个地方啊
DOCTOR: Maybe.
也许吧
JAMIE: Do you think this is sort of a trap, Doctor?
你觉得这是某种陷阱, 博士？
DOCTOR: Yes, but if only we knew who our enemies are...
是的, 要是我们知道我们的敌人是谁就好了。。。
Not the Chameleons again!
不会又是变色龙吧？
(注：在上一集04x08 The Faceless Ones出现)
DOCTOR: No, something else. I can feel them, closing in all around us.
不, 是其他的。我能感觉到, 就在我们旁边不远的地方
WATERFIELD: I've done everything that you've asked of me.
Isn't that enough?
我已经做了所有你要求我做的事情, 还不够吗？
WATERFIELD: Now you must tell me the truth. Do you hear?! The truth!
现在你必须告诉我真相, 听到没？真相！
WATERFIELD: But, you must tell me. I demand!
I'm talking to you! Come back!
不, 你必须告诉我！我强烈要求！我跟你说话呢！回来！
(Waterfield moves to a couch. He lies down and closes his eyes.)
(Waterfield 挪到一个躺椅上, 半躺下来, 闭上了眼睛)
JAMIE: Oh, if only the laird could see that!
Why do I get all the difficult tasks, Doctor?
哦, 要是领主看见这个就好了！为什么这些困难的任务总让我来, 博士？
DOCTOR: Because you're so much better at them than I am, Jamie.
What did you find out?
因为在这方面你比我强多了, Jamie。你发现什么了吗？
JAMIE: None of the lasses here could remember anybody called Ken or Kenneth.
这些女士们没一个记得谁叫做 Ken 或者 Kenneth
DOCTOR: Oh, dear.
哦, 天啊
JAMIE: Aye. But, they do have a different lot on duty in the evening.
Now, maybe they'll know.
是啊，不过，到了晚上又会是另外一批人，也许他们会知道
DOCTOR: Jamie, I'm being stared at. Is there something wrong with me?
Jamie，有人在盯着我看。我有什么地方不对劲吗？
JAMIE: You mean up here Doctor?
你是说在这个地方吗，博士？
DOCTOR: Is my hair in disarray?
我的头发乱了？
JAMIE: Well, no more than usual.
唔，没比平常乱
DOCTOR: Do I look strange or bizarre?
我看起来比较奇怪？
JAMIE: Aye. Well, maybe I'm just used to you.
啊，还好，也许我看你已经习惯了
DOCTOR: That's some comfort. Look out, he's coming over.
这我放心一点了。你看，他过来了
PERRY: I beg your pardon.
打扰一下
DOCTOR: Not at all.
没事
PERRY: It is Dr. Galloway, isn't it?
你是 Galloway 博士吗
DOCTOR: Dr. Gallo-?
Gallo...博士？
PERRY: ...and Mr. McCrimmon.
这位是 McCrimmon 先生
JAMIE: Aye, I'm Jamie McCrimmon.
是啊，我是 Jamie McCrimmon
PERRY: My card.
我的名片
JAMIE: Yes, uh...
好的，呃。。。
DOCTOR: Mr. Perry?
Perry 先生？
PERRY: Mr. Waterfield's frightfully sorry, but he can't meet you as arranged.
Waterfield 他表示非常抱歉，他不能来赴约了
DOCTOR: Oh. Oh, dear. What a pity.
哦，哦，太遗憾了
PERRY: But, he says if you'd care to come to the shop at about,
uh... ten tonight, he'll see to you personally.
不过，他说如果你愿意到店里来的话，呃。。今晚十点，他会跟你面谈
DOCTOR: At about 10. Oh, yes, uh... We'll be there.
大约10点是吧，哦，好的，呃。。。我们会到的
PERRY: Righto.
太好了
DOCTOR: Right! Right!
好，好
DOCTOR: "Edward Waterfield: Genuine Victoriana".
Edward Waterfield：维多利亚真品店
JAMIE: Can't be a mistake. Even though he got your name wrong, he knew mine.
应该没错了，虽然他把你的名字搞错了，他倒是知道我的
DOCTOR: I wonder if Mr. Kenneth has found us.
我在想 Kenneth 先生是不是发现了我们
JAMIE: Eh?
嗯？
DOCTOR: "K. Perry Esquire". Yes, I think we'll go and see Mr. Edward Waterfield.
"K. Perry Esquire". 是了，我想我们得去见 Edward Waterfield 先生
WATERFIELD: And he, uh... definitely said he would be here?
那他。。。的确说了他会来这里？
PERRY: Yes, sir.
是的，先生
WATERFIELD: Thank you. You have done excellently, Mr. Perry.
谢谢你，你做得很好，Perry 先生
PERRY: Er...
呃。。。
WATERFIELD: Good night.
晚安
PERRY: See you in the morning, sir.
明早见，先生
WATERFIELD: Uh, yes. Yes, in the morning.
啊，是的，早上见
(Waterfield watches Perry leave.)
(Waterfield 看着 Perry 离开)
WATERFIELD: Kennedy? Kennedy?
WATERFIELD: The Doctor is coming here tonight. I shall want you to help me.
And you had better put some warm clothes on. Dark things.
博士今晚要过来，我期望你帮我一下。你最好穿点厚衣服。有点脏活儿
WATERFIELD: All right. You'd better make sure that police box
is well covered-up, in case the Doctor starts snooping about.
这样，你最好把这个警亭好好遮掩起来，免得博士乱看
KENNEDY: Yes.
好的
(Waterfield leaves.)
(Waterfield 离开了)
(Kennedy takes a lock pick from his back pocket.)
(Kennedy 从口袋里面拿出一个撬锁器)
(He starts to pick the study door lock.)
(他开始撬书房门的锁)
(He picks the lock and enters the study.)
(他撬开了锁, 进了书房)
(He searches through all the desk drawers.)
(他在桌子抽屉里面翻找着)
(He then searches the rest of the room including the bookcase.)
(他又开始搜索房间的其它位置, 包括书架)
(He plays with switches on the control box.)
(他试探着控制箱上面的开关)
(but stops when the control lights begin to flicker.)
(一些控制灯开始闪烁, 他停了下来)
(He moves to a panel behind the chair.)
(他移动到椅子后面的面板旁)
DALEK: Who are you? Who are you? Answer!
你是谁？你是谁？回答！